Determining your skin type is easy and can help you in choosing cosmetics, moisturizers and cleansing products that are right for your type of skin.
I'm Jackie Silver with Aging Backwards with how to determine your skin type.
Wash your face with a mild cleanser, rinse it and pat dry.
Wait about one hour, note whether your face feels tight.
Press a tissue onto your chin, and look for an oily residue or a flaky skin residue.
Repeat the process with a new tissue each time on the center of your cheeks, your outer cheeks, the center of your forehead, outer forehead and your nose.
Oil on each tissue indicates an oily skin type.
While oil on some of the tissues such as the t zone which is the center of the forehead, the chin, nose and center of the cheeks, indicates combination skin.
Most of us have combination.
No oily or flaky residue of any kind indicates normal skin.
A tight feeling or flaky skin residue that's not oily indicates dry skin type.
Remember it's easy to determine your skin type with just a few tissues and a keen eye.
I'm Jackie Silver with how to determine your skin type.
Stay beautiful.